Register of the Russia. Missiia (Norway) Records, 1781-1924
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia. Missiia (Norway) Records,
1781-1924
XX775
Russia. Missiia (Norway)
128 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (55.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, financial records, and printed matter, relating to Russian-Norwegian trade and foreign relations, diplomacy during World War I and the Russian Revolution, and Russians in Norway. Includes records of the Russian consulate general in Kristiania before and after Norwegian independence; records of Russian consulates in other Norwegian cities; and records of the Russian mission in Sweden relating to Norway prior to Norwegian independence.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Russians--Norway; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918--Diplomatic history; Norway; Norway--Commerce--Russia; Norway--Foreign relations--Russia; Kristiania (Norway); Russia; Soviet Union; Russia--Commerce--Norway; Russia--Foreign relations--Norway; Soviet Union-History-Revolution, 1917-1921; Russia--Foreign relations--Sweden; Sweden--Foreign relations--Russia; Sweden
SERIES DESCRIPTION
- Correspondence, 1905-1923. (Boxes 1-13, 125)
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
- Subject File, 1905-1924. (Boxes 13-32, 126)
  Clippings, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, notes, printed matter, reports, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- General'Noe Konsul'Stvo, Christiania, 1781-1921. (Boxes 32-107, 128)
  Affidavits, clippings, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, notes, printed matter, registers, reports.
- Vitse-Konsul'Stvo, Bergen, 1887-1920. (Boxes 108-118.)
  Clippings, certificates, correspondence, financial records, personal identifications, poster, questionnaires, registers and reports.
- Vitse-Konsul'Stvo, Kristiansund, 1882-1913. (Box 118.)
  Correspondence, financial records, memoranda and questionnaires.
- Vitse-Konsul'Stvo, Mandal, 1881-1913. (Box 119.)
  Correspondence, financial records, memoranda, poster, printed matter and questionnaires.
- Vitse-Konsul'Stvo, Stavanger, 1816-1913. (Box 120.)
  Correspondence, memoranda, poster and printed matter.
- Vitse-Konsul'Stvo, Tonsberg, 1860-1913. (Box 120.)
  Financial records and printed matter.
- Vitse-Konsul'Stvo, Trondhjem, 1914-1922. (Box 120-122.)
  Correspondence, financial records and memoranda.
- Voennyi Agent, 1919-1920. (Box 123.)
  Correspondence and intelligence reports.
- Voenno-Morskoi Agent, 1916-1920. (Box 124.)
  Correspondence, financial records, lists of Navy officers, notes and questionnaires.
- Missiia (Sweden), 1895-1906. (Box 127.)
  Correspondence and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject. These materials were transferred to the Russian Mission in Norway from the Russian Mission in Sweden after Norwegian independence in 1905.
- Oversize File, 1916-1917. (Boxes129-130.)
  Correspondence, financial records, and registers.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1905-1923
  - General
    - Bound
      - 1905-1910 (Box 1., Folder 1)
      - 1910-1914 (Folder 2)
      - 1916 (Folder 3)
    - Unbound
      - 1905 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1906 (Folder 6-7)
      - 1907 (Folder 8)
      - 1908 (Folder 9)
      - 1909 (Folder 10)
      - 1910 (Folder 11)
      - 1911 (Folder 12)
      - 1912 (Folder 13)
  - Aktieselkabel Lorentzen & Wettre, 1915-1916 (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - Austria. Legation (Denmark), 1909 (Folder 2)
  - Bachke & Co., 1915 (Folder 3)
  - Bennett's Tourist Bureau, 1915 (Folder 4)
  - Centralbanken for Norge, 1916-1917 (Folder 5)
  - Cuba. Legation (Norway), 1917 (Folder 6)
  - Czechoslovakia. Legation (Romania), 1923 (Folder 7)
  - Engineering Products Corporation, 1915 (Folder 8)
  - Fougners Staal-Beton Skibsbygningskompani, 1916 (Folder 9)
  - France. Consulate (Trondhjem), 1914-1915 (Folder 10)
  - France. Legation (Norway), 1915-1922 (Folder 11)
  - General'noe konsul'stvo, CHristiania
    - 1910-1915 (Folder 12)
    - 1916 (Folder 13)
    - 1917-1920 (Folder 14)
  - Great Britain. Legation (Norway), 1915-1917 (Folder 15)
  - Greece. Consulate General (CHristiania), 1921 (Folder 16)
  - Heitman, H. & Son, 1915 (Folder 17)
  - Helly I. Hansen, 1915 (Folder 18)
  - Italy, Legation (Norway), 1919 (Folder 19)
  - Johansen, Ingv., 1914 (Folder 20)
  - Jordan, Thomas M., 1914 (Folder 21)
  - Kamenev, General, n.d. (Folder 22)
  - Klose & Seidel Bureau fuer Zeitungs-Ausschnitte, 1912 (Folder 23)
  - Kobro & Co., 1915 (Folder 24)
  - Kommercheskii agent in Germany, 1913 (Folder 25)
  - Kommercheskii agent in Norway
    - 1913-1917 (Folder 26)
    - 1919-1921 (Folder 27)
  - Kommercheskii agent in Sweden and Denmark, 1916 (Folder 2)
  - Konsul'stvo, Alesund, 1916 (Folder 29)
  - Konsul'stvo, Bergen
    - 1906-1915 (Folder 30)
    - 1916 (Folder 31)
    - 1917-1919 (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - Konsul'stvo, Hammerfest
    - 1906-1915 (Folder 2)
    - 1916-1919 (Folder 3)
  - Konsul'stvo, Stavanger, 1916 (Folder 4)
  - Konsul'stvo, Tromso, 1916-1920 (Folder 5)
  - Konsul'stvo, Trondhjem, 1916-1920 (Folder 6)
  - Konsul'stvo, Vardo, 1911-1917 (Folder 7)
  - Langraner, C. & Co., 1914 (Folder 8)
  - Lie, E.A., 1914 (Folder 9)
  - Lorentzen, Chr., 1916 (Folder 10)
  - L'vov, Prince Georgii Evgen'evich, 1914 (Folder 11)
  - Mexico. Legation (Norway), 1919 (Folder 12)
  - Mikhail Aleksandrovich, Grand Duke, 1906 (Folder 13)
  - Ministerstvo finansov, 1916-1917 (Folder 14)
  - Ministerstvo inostrannykh del, including Russian diplomatic agencies abroad. See also General'noe konsul'stvo, CHristiania; Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Alesund; Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Bergen; Vitse-Konsul'stvo, Stavanger;Vitse- Konsul'stvo, Trondhjem
    - Undated (Folder 15)
    - 1905 (Folder 16)
    - 1906
      - January (Folder 17)
      - February (Folder 18)
      - March (Folder 19)
      - April (Folder 20)
      - May (Folder 21)
      - June (Folder 22)
      - July (Folder 23)
      - August (Box 4., Folder 1)
      - September (Folder 2)
      - October (Folder 3)
      - November (Folder 4)
      - December (Folder 5)
    - 1907
      - January (Folder 6)
      - February (Folder 7)
      - March (Folder 8)
      - April (Folder 9)
      - May (Folder 10)
      - June (Folder 11)
      - July (Folder 12)
      - August (Folder 13)
      - September (Folder 14)
      - October (Folder 15)
      - November (Folder 16)
      - December (Folder 17)
    - 1908
      - January (Folder 18)
      - February (Folder 19)
      - March (Folder 20)
      - April (Folder 21)
      - May (Folder 22)
      - June (Folder 23)
      - July (Folder 24)
      - August (Folder 25)
      - September (Folder 26)
      - October (Box 5., Folder 1)
      - November (Folder 2)
      - December (Folder 3)
    - 1909
      - January (Folder 4)
      - February (Folder 5)
      - March (Folder 6)
      - April (Folder 7)
      - May (Folder 8)
      - June (Folder 9)
      - July (Folder 10)
      - August (Folder 11)
      - September (Folder 12)
      - October (Folder 13)
      - November (Folder 14)
      - December (Folder 15)
    - 1910
      - January (Folder 16)
      - February (Folder 17)
      - March (Folder 18)
      - April (Folder 19)
      - May (Folder 20)
      - June (Folder 21)
      - July (Folder 22)
      - August (Folder 23)
      - September (Folder 24)
      - October (Folder 25)
      - November (Box 6., Folder 1)
      - December (Folder 2)
    - 1911
      - January (Folder 3)
      - February (Folder 4)
      - March (Folder 5)
      - April (Folder 6)
      - May (Folder 7)
      - June (Folder 8)
      - July (Folder 9)
      - August (Folder 10)
      - September (Folder 11)
      - October (Folder 12)
      - November (Folder 13)
      - December (Folder 14)
    - 1912
      - January (Folder 15)
      - February (Folder 16)
      - March (Folder 17)
      - April (Folder 18)
      - May (Folder 19)
      - June (Folder 20)
      - July (Folder 21)
      - August (Folder 22)
      - September (Folder 23)
      - October (Folder 24)
      - November (Folder 25)
      - December (Folder 26)
    - 1913 (Folder 27)
    - 1914 (Folder 28)
    - 1915
      - January (Box 7., Folder 1)
      - February (Folder 2)
      - March (Folder 3)
      - April (Folder 4)
      - May (Folder 5)
      - June (Folder 6)
      - July (Folder 7)
      - August (Folder 8)
      - September (Folder 9)
      - October (Folder 10)
      - November (Folder 11)
      - December (Folder 12)
    - 1916
      - General
        - January (Folder 13)
        - February (Folder 14)
        - March (Folder 15)
        - April (Folder 16)
        - May (Folder 17)
        - June (Folder 18)
        - July (Folder 19)
        - August (Folder 20)
        - September (Folder 21)
        - October (Box 8., Folder 1)
        - November
          - Handwritten and typewritten (Folder 2)
          - Printed (Folder 3)
        - December (Folder 4)
      - Registers (Folder 5)
    - 1917
      - General
        - No month indicated (Folder 6)
        - January (Folder 7)
        - February (Folder 8)
        - March (Folder 9)
        - April (Box 9., Folder 1)
        - May (Folder 2)
        - June (Folder 3)
        - July (Folder 4)
        - August (Folder 5)
        - September (Folder 6)
        - October (Folder 7-8)
        - November (Folder 9)
        - December (Box 10., Folder 1)
      - Registers (Folder 2)
    - 1918 (Folder 3)
    - 1919
      - No month indicated (Folder 4)
      - January (Folder 5)
      - February (Folder 6)
      - March (Folder 7)
      - April (Folder 8)
      - May (Folder 9)
      - June (Folder 10)
      - July (Folder 11)
      - August (Folder 12)
      - September (Folder 13)
      - October (Folder 14)
      - November (Folder 15)
      - December (Folder 16)
    - 1920
      - No month indicated (Folder 17)
      - January (Folder 18)
      - February (Folder 19)
      - March (Folder 20)
      - April (Folder 21)
      - May (Folder 22)
      - June (Folder 23)
      - July (Folder 24)
      - August (Folder 25)
      - September (Folder 26)
      - October (Folder 27)
      - November (Folder 28)
      - December (Folder 29)
    - 1921 (Box 11., Folder 1)
    - 1922 (Folder 2)
    - 1923 (Folder 3)
  - Ministerstvo putei soobshcheniia (Folder 4)
  - Ministerstvo torgovli i promyshlennosti, 1912-1917 (Folder 5)
  - Ministerstvo torgovli i promyshlennosti. Representative in Germany. See Kommercheskii agent in Germany
  - Ministerstvo torgovli i promyshlennosti. Representative in Norway. See Kommercheskii agent in Norway
  - Ministerstvo torgovli i promyshlennosti. Representative in Sweden and Denmark. See Kommercheskii agent in Sweden and Denmark
  - Ministerstvo vnutrennikh del, 1910 (Folder 6)
  - Ministerstvo vnutrennikh del. Departament politsii
    - 1907 (Folder 7)
    - 1908 (Folder 8)
    - 1909 (Folder 9)
    - 1910 (Folder 10)
    - 1911
      - January (Folder 11)
      - February (Folder 12)
      - March (Folder 13)
      - April (Folder 14)
      - May (Folder 15)
      - June (Folder 16)
      - July (Folder 17)
      - August (Folder 18)
      - September (Box 12., Folder 1)
    - 1916 (Folder 2)
  - Morskoe ministerstvo. Representative in Norway. See Voenno-morskoi agent
  - Mowinckel, J. Ludwig, 1916 (Folder 3)
  - Nordisk Resebureau, 1914 (Folder 4)
  - Norsk Hydro-Elektrisk Kvaelstofaktieselskab, 1917 (Folder 5)
  - Norske Lloyd, 1914 (Folder 6)
  - Northdwina & Murmancoast, Ltd., 1919 (Folder 7)
  - Portugal. Legation (Norway), 1917 (Folder 8)
  - Romania. Legation (Norway), 1917-1919 (Folder 9)
  - Russkii pravitel'stvennyi komitet, London, 1916-1917 (Folder 10)
  - Severin, Karl, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - Sibirskoe aktsionernoe obshchestvo parokhodstva, promyshlennosti i torgovli, 1915 (Folder 12)
  - Sweden. Legation (Norway), 1917 (Folder 13)
  - Svenska Patentkorkfabriken, 1915 (Folder 14)
  - United States. Legation (Norway), 1915-1917 (Folder 15)
  - Utenriksdepartementet
    - 1905 (Folder 16)
    - 1906 (Folder 17)
    - 1907 (Folder 18)
    - 1908 (Folder 19)
    - 1909 (Folder 20)
    - 1910 (Folder 21)
    - 1911 (Folder 22)
    - 1912 (Folder 23)
    - 1913 (Folder 24)
    - 1914 (Folder 25)
    - 1915 (Folder 26)
    - 1916 (Box 13., Folder 1)
    - 1917 (Folder 2)
    - 1918 (Folder 3)
    - 1919 (Folder 4)
    - 1920 (Folder 5)
  - Viking Canning Co., 1916 (Folder 6)
  - Voennoe ministerstvo. Representative in Denmark, Sweden, and Norway. See Voennyi agent
  - Voenno-morskoi agent, 1914-1919 (Folder 7)
  - Voennyi agent, 1908-1920 (Folder 8)
  - Vserossiiskii zemskii soiuz pomoshchi ranenym voinam Tverskoi gubernii, 1915 (Folder 9)
  - Wladyslaw Hoffman & Co., 1915 (Folder 10)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1905-1924
  - General
    - Runolfsson, E.
      - Clippings (Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1913-1917 (Folder 12)
      - Notebooks (Folder 13-14)
    - Savitskii. Correspondence, mostly with Ministerstvo inostrannykh del, 1916-1917 (Box 14., Folder 1-3)
  - Aare, Jakob (Folder 4)
  - Abrahamson, Gunar (Folder 5)
  - Administration and management
    - General
      - Undated (Folder 6)
      - 1905 (Folder 7)
      - 1906 (Folder 8)
      - 1906-1907 (Folder 9)
      - 1907 (Folder 10)
      - 1908 (Folder 11)
      - 1909 (Folder 12)
      - 1910 (Folder 13)
      - 1910-1911 (Folder 14)
      - 1911-1912 (Folder 15)
      - 1912 (Box 15., Folder 1)
      - 1912-1913 (Folder 2)
      - 1913 (Folder 3)
      - 1913-1914 (Folder 4)
      - 1914 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1914-1915 (Folder 7)
      - 1915 (Folder 8)
      - 1915-1916 (Folder 9)
      - 1916 (Box 16., Folder 1)
      - 1917 (Folder 2)
      - 1918 (Folder 3)
      - 1919 (Folder 4)
      - 1920 (Folder 5)
      - 1921 (Folder 6)
    - Financial records
      - 1906 (Folder 7)
      - 1907 (Folder 8)
      - 1908 (Folder 9)
      - 1909 (Folder 10)
      - 1910 (Folder 11)
      - 1911 (Folder 12)
      - 1912 (Folder 13)
      - 1913 (Folder 14)
      - 1914 (Box 17., Folder 1)
      - 1915 (Folder 2)
      - 1916 (Folder 3-4)
      - 1917 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1918 (Folder 7)
      - 1918 (Box 18., Folder 1)
      - 1919 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1920 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1921 (Folder 6)
      - 1922 (Folder 7)
      - 1923 (Folder 8)
      - 1924 (Folder 9)
  - Amundsen, Roald (Folder 10)
  - Armenians (Folder 11)
  - Artificial limbs (Folder 12)
  - Automobiles (Folder 13)
  - Baltic states (Folder 14)
  - Belavanets, P.I. (Folder 15)
  - Bessarabia (Folder 16)
  - Censorship -- Immoral literature (Folder 17)
  - Commerce (mostly Russian)
    - General
      - 1905 (Folder 18)
      - 1906 (Folder 19)
      - 1907 (Box 19., Folder 1)
      - 1910 (Folder 2)
      - 1912 (Folder 3)
      - 1913 (Folder 4)
      - 1914 (Folder 5)
      - 1915 (Folder 6-9)
      - 1916 (Folder 10-13)
      - 1917 (Box 20., Folder 1)
      - 1918 (Folder 2)
      - 1919 (Folder 3)
      - 1920 (Folder 4)
    - Government policies during World War I
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Ministerstvo torgovli i promyshlennosti. Komitet po ogranicheniiu snabzheniia i torgovli nepriiatelia
        - Printed matter (Folder 6-7)
        - Typewritten materials (Folder 8)
      - Ministerstvo torgovli i promyshlennosti. Russkii chernyi spisok(1916-1917), 1917 (Folder 9)
    - Hemp (Folder 10)
    - Lubricants (Folder 11)
    - Lumber (Folder 12)
    - Murmansk railway (Folder 13)
  - Copyright, International (Folder 14)
  - Eriksen, William (Folder 15)
  - Finland (Folder 16)
  - Firemen. Report of the Committee of Organization of the 6th International Firemen Congress, Petersburg, 1912 (Folder 17)
  - Fur seal hunters (Folder 18)
  - Ganzen, Petr Gotfridovich (Folder 19)
  - Gundersen, Johan Gustav (Folder 20)
  - Hansen, Karl (Folder 21)
  - Heiberg, Hermann (Folder 22)
  - Hiortdahl, Samuel (Folder 23)
  - Homelessness (Box 21., Folder 1)
  - Horticulture -- International Horticulture Exhibition, 1914 (Folder 2)
  - Imperatorskii vserossiiskii aero-klub (Folder 3)
  - Insurance (Folder 4)
  - Istomin, Andrei (Folder 5)
  - Kajander, Andrei (Folder 6)
  - Kajander, Kalle (Folder 7)
  - Kallenberg, Peter (Folder 8)
  - Knudsen (Folder 9)
  - Krstich, IA.M. (Folder 10)
  - Kvalheim, A. (Folder 11)
  - Lapps
    - 1905 (Folder 12)
    - 1906 (Folder 13)
    - 1907 (Folder 14)
    - 1908 (Folder 15)
    - 1909 (Folder 16)
    - 1910 (Folder 17)
    - 1911 (Folder 18)
    - 1913 (Folder 19)
    - 1914 (Folder 20)
  - League of Nations (Folder 21)
  - Lunde, O. (Folder 22)
  - Lundevall, Tarald Andreas. See Gundersen, Johan Gustav
  - Marstander (Folder 23)
  - Ministerstvo inostrannykh del
    - General (Folder 24)
    - Komissiia po reorganizatsii zagranichnoi sluzhby MID (Box 22., Folder 1)
  - Missiia in Greece (Folder 2)
  - Munte, Johan (Folder 3)
  - Nobel prizes (Folder 4)
  - Norsk Bjergningskompagni (Folder 5)
  - Norway
    - General
      - Printed matter
        - General (Folder 6-10)
        - General (Box 23., Folder 1-2)
        - Map (Folder 3)
    - Agriculture (Folder 4)
    - Alcoholism (Folder 5)
    - Armed forces (Folder 6)
    - Coronation of Haakon VII, 1906 (Folder 7)
    - Economic conditions (Folder 8)
    - Foreign relations
      - Diplomatic missions in Christiania (Folder 9)
      - Independence, 1905 (Folder 10)
      - Neutrality
        - General (Folder 11)
        - World War I (Folder 12)
      - Warships in Norwegian ports
        - General (Folder 13)
        - German Navy (Folder 14)
    - Pharmacy (Folder 15)
  - Nyquist, Colonel (Folder 16)
  - Peace and international security -- Second Peace Conference, Haague, 1906 (Folder 17)
  - Planting, Aksel Wilhelm (Box 24., Folder 1)
  - Postal service -- International Postal Convention, 1906 (Folder 2)
  - Prisons -- International Prison Commission, 1911-1915 (Folder 3)
  - Pushkarev, Akim (Folder 4)
  - Rasputin, Grigorii -- Assassination plan (Folder 5)
  - Relief of sick and wounded -- Convention on Improvement of Conditions of Wounded and Sick Soldiers during the Land Warfare, Geneva, 1906. See also World War I/Relief of sick and wounded (Folder 6)
  - Russia. See Soviet Union
  - Russian church (Folder 7)
  - Russians outside Russia
    - General
      - Undated (Folder 8)
      - 1907 (Folder 9)
      - 1908 (Folder 10)
      - 1909 (Folder 11)
      - 1910 (Folder 12)
      - 1911 (Folder 13)
      - 1912 (Folder 14)
      - 1913 (Folder 15)
      - 1914 (Folder 16)
      - 1915
        - January (Folder 17)
        - February (Folder 18)
        - March (Folder 19)
        - April (Folder 20)
        - May (Folder 21)
        - June (Folder 22)
        - July (Folder 23)
        - August (Folder 24)
        - September (Folder 25)
        - October (Folder 26)
        - November (Box 25., Folder 1)
        - December (Folder 2)
      - 1916
        - January (Folder 3)
        - February (Folder 4)
        - March (Folder 5)
        - April (Folder 6)
        - May (Folder 7)
        - June (Folder 8)
        - July (Folder 9)
        - August (Folder 10)
        - September (Folder 11)
        - October (Folder 12)
        - November (Box 26., Folder 1)
        - December (Folder 2)
      - 1917
        - No month indicated (Folder 3)
        - January (Folder 4)
        - February (Folder 5)
        - March (Folder 6)
        - April (Folder 7)
        - May (Folder 8)
        - June (Folder 9)
        - July (Folder 10)
        - August (Folder 11)
        - September (Folder 12)
        - October (Folder 13)
        - November (Folder 14)
      - 1918 (Folder 15)
      - 1919 (Folder 16)
      - 1920 (Folder 17)
      - 1921 (Folder 18)
      - 1922 (Folder 19)
      - 1923 (Folder 20)
    - Amosov, Fedor (Folder 21)
    - Bakai, Mikhail (Folder 22)
    - Balabanov, Evgenii (Folder 23)
    - Berzin vs. Vellin (Folder 24)
    - Blokh, Konstantin (Folder 25)
    - Books. List of books to be sent to Lilehammer (Folder 26)
    - Brink, Emilie (Folder 27)
    - CHernov, Petr (Folder 28)
    - Dmitriev, Vasilii Vasil'evich (Folder 29)
    - Dudko, Ivan (Folder 30)
    - Frantseva, Valentina (Box 27., Folder 1)
    - IUshkovich, Sofiia (Folder 2)
    - Kaaran, A.A. (Folder 3)
    - Kamenetskii, Nikolai (Folder 4)
    - Kulikov, Sergei Ivanovich (Folder 5)
    - League of Nations (Folder 6)
    - Livshin, L.L. (Folder 7)
    - Lipping, Edward (Folder 8)
    - Martilla, Auguste Johansson (Folder 9)
    - Organizations
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Krasnyi krest
        - Undated (Folder 11)
        - 1916 (Folder 12)
        - 1919 (Folder 13)
        - 1920 (Folder 14)
        - 1921 (Folder 15)
        - 1922 (Folder 16)
        - 1923 (Folder 17)
        - 1924 (Folder 18)
      - Obshchestvo sluzhashchikh MID (Folder 19)
      - Rossiiskaia torgovaia palata (Folder 20)
      - Russkii komitet pomoshchi emigrantu -- tuberkuleznomu, invalidu i detiam-sirotam pri uchastii Germanskogo krasnogo kresta (Folder 21)
      - Russkii natsional'nyi komitet (Folder 22)
      - Vremennyi komitet po delam bezhentsev Severnoi oblasti (Folder 23)
    - Petrov (Folder 24)
    - Provisional Government of Northern Province vs Glazenap (Folder 25)
    - Sidorova, Natal'ia Arkad'evna (Box 28., Folder 1)
    - Sotland, Movsha (Folder 2)
    - Springfeld, Samuel (Folder 3)
    - Trufanov, Sergei Mikhailovich (Folder 4)
    - Tyrtova, Natal'ia (Folder 5)
    - Wasel, Eric (Folder 6)
  - Ships
    - Eclips (Folder 7)
    - Kit. See Eclips
    - Konstantsia (Folder 8)
    - Paria (Folder 9)
    - Sv. Nikolai (Folder 10)
    - Vasilii Velikii (Folder 11)
    - Viking (Folder 12)
  - Soika (Folder 13)
  - Sommer, M. (Folder 14)
  - Soviet Union. Includes materials on the pre- 1917 period
    - General (Folder 15)
    - Economic, social, and political conditions, 1917-1923 (Folder 16)
    - Education, 1918 (Folder 17)
    - Famine, 1921-1922 (Folder 18)
    - Foreign relations. See also SUBJECT FILE/Soviet Union/Revolution and Civil War
      - General. Review, 1922 (Folder 19)
      - Denmark, 1909 (Folder 20)
      - Germany, 1916-1917 (Folder 21)
      - Great Britain, 1918-1923 (Folder 22)
      - Japan, 1907-1922. See also SUBJECT FILE/Soviet Union/Russo-Japanese War Memorial, 1909 (Folder 23)
      - Norway, 1911-1917 (Box 29., Folder 1)
      - Switzerland, 1908 (Folder 2)
    - Foreign warships in Russian ports. Rules and regulations, 1913 (Folder 3)
    - Foreigners in Russia, 1909-1914 (Folder 4)
    - Intelligence service (Folder 5)
    - Revolution and Civil War
      - General. Includes three 1918 essays by W. de Hueck (Folder 6)
      - Far East (Folder 7)
      - North -- Provisional Government of the Northern Province. Includes correspondence among Russian consulates in Norway
        - Undated (Folder 8)
        - 1918, including N. CHaikovskii, Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller (Folder 9-14)
        - 1919
          - General (Folder 15-16)
          - January (Box 126., Folder 1)
          - February (Folder 2)
          - March (Folder 3)
          - April (Folder 4)
          - May (Folder 5)
          - June (Folder 6)
          - July (Folder 7)
          - August (Folder 8)